Discover what happens when you go looking for a miracle
and a miracle comes looking for you.
Because of Winn-Dixie is a family, comedy, drama film directed by Wayne Wang.
A girl, abandoned by her mother when she was three, moves
to a small town in Florida with her father.
There, she adopts an orphaned dog she names Winn-Dixie.
The bond between the girl and her special companion brings together the people in a
small Florida town and heals her own troubled relationship with her father.
Preacher, played by Jeff Daniels.
Opal, played by AnnaSophia Robb.
Gloria Dump, played by Cicely Tyson.
Miss Franny, played by Eva Marie Saint.
Otis, played by Dave Matthews.
Amanda Wilkenson, played by Courtney Jines.
Because of Winn-Dixie is a 2005 American comedy-drama film based on Kate DiCamillo's 2000 novel of the same name,
with the screenplay written by Joan Singleton, produced by Trevor Albert and directed by Wayne Wang.
The film was produced by Walden Media and released by 20th Century Fox.
Because of Winn-Dixie stars Jeff Daniels, Cicely Tyson, Eva Marie Saint,
Dave Matthews and AnnaSophia Robb in her feature film debut.
It premiered at the USA Film Festival on January 26, 2005, and
was theatrically released on February 18, 2005.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and earned $33.5
million against a production budget of $14 million.
It was released on DVD and VHS on August 9, 2005 by
20th Century Fox Home Entertainment.
The film explores themes of dog, pets, father daughter relationship.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.